♪ Oh, yeah
Amma. How's your foot?
阿妈 你的脚怎么样了
Oh, I'm fine, beta. Don't worry about me.
我好着呢 宝贝 不要操心我
But if you want to worry,
不过你要是真的担心我
worry about making me a grandmother.
操心操心怎么让我当上奶奶吧
Like all my friends are.
我所有的朋友都当奶奶了
Is it around having child...
都在说孩子...
♪ Oh, yeah
He never remembers the previous day?
他不会记得前一天的事吗
For him, there is no yesterday.
对他来说 是没有昨天的
Or not one that matters.
或者说之前一天并不重要
First-class continuations don't save program data,
一阶延续计算不会储存程序数据
only the... execution context.
只储存执行环境
Is the call from Mother necessary?
他妈妈打来那个电话有什么存在的必要吗
Emotion is important for creative problem-solving.
情感是创新型解决问题的过程中重要的一环
Sir...
先生
And adding back emotion is what made the others useless.
再把情感加回来 会使别的功能失效的
Yes, sir, but those emotions were too strong, ungoverned.
老板 您说得没错
但是这些情感太强烈了 没办法控制
They took over.
情感会把控住整个程序
For Chanda, we specifically simulated this call
我们为钱达量身定制了他妈妈打来的这个电话
from his mother to incentivize progress via social utility...
通过社交能力来激励程序演算
Don't talk Cambridgeto me.
别跟我扯这些鸟语
I'm from the chawls.
我是一路打拼来的
It's love, but with just enough annoyance to keep on task.
这种情感是爱
但是为了整个程序 它已经经过缜密处理
Sir.
老板
Good man.
干得好
Speed him up.
让他干快点
An 80-page patent written in 15 seconds?
他15秒就写好了80页专利文件吗
For him, it was 12 days.
对他来说 这是12天的工作量
No... for him, it was one.
不 对他来说 是一天的工作量
Dad?!
爸爸
啊
Aah!
A little help here!
我需要一点帮助
Aah!
WoWhen I was 10,
我十岁的时候
my dad and I would play "Reign of Winter"
我和我爸爸在周日他结束工作之后
会一起玩冬日王朝这个游戏
on Sundays when he was done with work.
现在他已经不在人世了
Now that he's no longer alive...
we get to play almost every day.
我们却可以每天都一起玩游戏
这个游戏也更新了很多地方
"Reign of Winter" has come a long way, too...
完全支持虚拟现实交互技术 触感穿戴设备
Full VR, haptic modeling.
玩起来就像是你真的在游戏场景里一样
It's like you're really there.
Hey, where were you?
嘿 你之前跑哪儿去了
该死的奇美拉差点把我当早饭吃了
Damn Chimera almost had me for breakfast.
我之前就在这儿呢
I was here.
Dad...
爸爸...
And I was scanning
我之前在扫描
the Shenzhen index for signs of Laurie.
深圳综指 寻找劳瑞留下的痕迹
怎么啦 你说的她之前是华尔街交易员 我没记错吧
What? You said she was a Wall Street trader, right?
我想她可能藏在股票交易所的服务器里
I thought maybe she was hiding out in a stock exchange.
我很确定劳瑞准备好联系你的时候她会找你的
I'm sure when Laurie's ready to contact you, she will.
你得承认这很奇怪
Just admit that it's weird.
她帮我从字符律动逃了出来
She helps me escape Logorhythms,
还帮我建了一个加密服务器让我能藏在这儿
sets up a secure server block for me to hide on,
但是却连个招呼都不和我打吗
and never even says hi?
她这样的确有点奇怪
She is weird.
她丈夫的举止也很奇怪
Her husband was weird, too.
可能是因为我吧
Maybe it's me.
It's almost like a guy gets uploaded,
一个大脑被上载变成程序的家伙
是个女人都不想和我说话
and women don't want to talk to him anymore.
I told you.
我跟你说过
妈妈只是需要时间来适应
Mom just needs time.
这才过去几天呢
It's only been a few days.
麦蒂 时间流逝的速度对我来说是不一样的
Time doesn't move at the same speed for me, Maddie.
You know how long "a few days" feels?
你知道几天对我来说是多久吗
I'm... I'm not sure if we know how anything feels for you.
我···我觉得我们在任何事情上都不能和你感同身受
Is that it, then? She doesn't think I'm human?
是这样吗 她没把我当人看吗
I didn't say that.
我不是这拿意思
She's super busy right now.
她最近超级忙
She's had to work a lot more hours since you...
她得工作很久很久 自从你...
And also, she hates VR, okay?
对了 她讨厌VR 你记得吧
It makes her nauseous.
她会头晕恶心
Dad?
爸爸
Hello?
你说话啊
It's die time!
受死吧
It's another party.
是另一伙人
They look high-level.
他们看起来等级很高
Whoa! What the hell?
哇 这是什么情况啊
What the hell was that?!
这是什么情况啊
What the hell was that?
这是什么情况
Signature burst. It was one of them.
数字签名爆了 是他们中的一个
Can we track it?
我们可以追踪吗
韦斯曼还没写出来追踪程序
Waxman is not done writing the tracking program yet.
Just record the spike, and we'll send it for analysis.
先把激增情况记录下来 之后再把它送去分析
I told you, only do moves a regular player could do.
我跟你说过 你只能做一个普通玩家能做的事情
If the mods find out you're in the code...
如果管理员发现你在代码里...
You're worried I'll get banned.
你担心我会被禁止登陆游戏
我是担心你会被盯上
I'm worried you'll be hunted by, like,
the NSA or something!
国家安全局或者其它机构会追踪你
Dad, no one can know you exist.
爸爸 没有人能知道你的存在
对我妻子来说 我不算个人
Well, according to my wife, I don't.
I'll talk to her.
我会和她谈谈的
Okay?
好吗
每个个体都将是
Each individual will be the god
自己独创小天地的主宰
of their own customizable heaven.
在这个小天地里 不再缺少任何东西
A world beyond scarcity.
不再有贫富之分
A world without rich or poor.
不再有持强凌弱
Without exclusion or possession.
A world without death.
不再有死亡
想想看
Just imagine.
It's easy if you try.
试了才知道这有简单
这才是真正原创的东西
Yeah. Realoriginal.
I-I know it's none of my business.
我...我知道这不关我的事
我想告诉你 你现在的情况
I just want you to know that what you're dealing with
并不正常
is not normal.
你不该经历这些事的
And you shouldn't have to go through it.
At least, not alone.
至少不该自己承担这些
- 所以··· - 你说得对
So... You're right,
it's none of your business.
这不关你的事
Second attack in a week...
这周的第二次攻击
他们说损失了十亿美元
They're saying billion-dollar loss.
我觉得不止这个数
I think it's more. No one's claimed it yet?
可能是中国人干的
Maybe it's the Chinese.
我听说他们在测试一个上传人脑的程序
"I heard they're testing a program to upload human brains."
Caspian?
凯斯宾
妈妈 你吓到我了
Mom. You scared me.
I'm sneaky like that.
我就是这么神出鬼没
Whatcha lookin' at?
你在看什么呢
Nothing. School stuff.
没什么 学校的作业
Look...
那个...
about the other day...
那天
with your father and me...
你爸爸和我
Uploaded intelligence, actually, is what I'm looking at.
其实我在看上载智能的资料
What's that?
那是什么
You know how I upload the data on your laptop to the cloud,
你知道吧 我把你笔记本电脑的数据都上传到云端了
in case it crashes?
以免电脑崩溃丢失数据
这两者很相似 不过那些数据
It's like that, but with the data
that's stored in humans.
是储存在人脑里的
Memories, feelings, skills, everything.
记忆 感觉 技能 一切
Is this a movie or something?
是电影小说之类的东西吗
No, remember Stephen Holstrom?
不是这样 你还记得斯蒂芬．霍尔斯特隆吗
Here's him talking about it, back in 2001, before he died.
这是2001年他去世之前讲到的
所以 如果字符律动继续在这个方向开展研究 那么...
So, if Logorhythms was working on it way back then...
Logorhythms?
字符律动
The microchip company?
那家生产微型芯片的公司吗
You seriously think they're turning people
你真的觉得他们把人
into... brain clouds now
变成了云端脑集台
in Silicon Valley?
储存在硅谷吗
妈妈 这不是云端脑集台 这是...
It's not brain clouds, Mom, and it...
Wait, it wouldn't be in Palo Alto.
等等 地点不该在帕洛阿尔托
That's for sure... If they're really doing this,
肯定是这样 如果他们真的在做这件事
一定会选一个遥远的地方 比如海外
it would be way off-site, like overseas.
人体试验的规定更少 更难追踪资金
Fewer regs on human trials, harder to trace the money.
I know you said stick to the plan, but I think he's
我知道你会说计划不变
但他在搜索数据中心 他在看斯蒂芬的视频
searching for the data center. He's watching videos
of Stephen, and... And we're watching
而我们正在监视他
everything he's watching.
看的所有内容
蕾妮...
Renee...
Breathe.
放松
Focus on tomorrow.
明天盯紧他
这是青春期最重要的
This is the most critical inflection
转折点了
point of his adolescence.
你得把这件事放在首位
We need you on top of things.
So does he.
你丈夫也一样
Mmm.
老兄 你怎么了
What happened to you, man?
重置
Reset.
♪ Oh, yeah
这活儿不用两个人干 卡里
This is not a two-person job, Cary.
Pick a goddamn hammer and be done with it.
买个破锤子不就完事儿了
You make it a two-person job because whatever I pick
是你让非要来的 因为无论我买什么
is somehow gonna be wrong.
都会无缘无故买错
And I'm not driving back out here again
我不想因为你不喜欢锤子握把之类的理由
because you don't like the grip or something.
半路开回来买新的了
This is the most critical inflection point
这是他青春期最关键的转折点
of his adolescence; the hammer at home is filthy.
家里那把锤子已经脏的不行
Take some pride in your last day of work.
你好好站完最后一班岗吧
It's interesting.
真有意思
G major, but it never hits the tonic chord of its key.
G大调 但从来没有弹到主音和弦
It's an intriguing pattern, almost like a...
真是个有趣的模式 就像是...
Almost like a recursive loop.
一个递归的循环
Maybe that's how I can solve memory allocation.
也许这样能让我记忆集中一点呢
Recursion.
递归
I love the way your mind works.
真喜欢你的思考
内外兼修 身材也很有料呢
And your body's not too bad, either.
嗯 待会儿我想解开隐马尔可夫模型的谜题
Mm, later I want to work out that Hidden Markov Model idea.
我想 对于突破肉身束缚来说 这点至关重要
I think it'll be vital to cracking integrity.
If anyone can do it, you can.
要说谁能做到 那非你莫属
Just imagine existing in a universe
想象一下 存在于无垠宇宙之间
却不受肉体束缚
unencumbered by this.
♪ Home is where I want to be
I don't know.
我不知道呢
人的肉体还是有点好处的
There are still some benefits to physicality.
Limited.
有限的
在云端 我们能触碰到
In the cloud, we'll be able to tap into senses
过去从未意识到的感官 如同想象一场
we never knew we had... Imagine the best sex
you've ever had.
你从未尝试过的 无与伦比的性爱
然后重复想象百万遍
Now imagine that a million times over,
for eternity.
直至永远
Don't get it.
别管了
It's Cary.
是卡里
Do you want to...
你要不要...
Here are the papers, Mr. Holstrom.
这些是文件 霍尔斯特隆先生
Oh. I'll come back for them in the morning.
啊 明早我再给您送过来吧
No, I'll sign them now.
不用了 我现在就签了吧
Just give me a sec.
等我一下
Here you go...
给你
dear.
亲爱的
I told you, I don't like that one.
我说了 我不喜欢这把
Yeah.
我知道
That's what sold me on it.
我故意的
See you at home.
家里见
Every time.
每次都这样
Why are people so scared of you?
那些人为什么怕你
No one likes a girl whose weight and IQ
没人喜欢一个体重和智商
都超过115的女生
are both over 115.
I'm intimidating.
我很吓人
I don't think so.
我可不这么觉得
Then why did you ask me, out of
那你为什么从茫茫女生中
800 other girls you don't know,
挑申了我
来当你的保镖 保护你不受成年男子伤害呢
to be the bodyguard who protects you from an adult man?
Shit.
靠
这很正常 我和你们一样爱指手画脚
It's fine. I'm as judgy as the rest of you.
But remarkably better at it.
不过比你们优越得多罢了
What are you up to tonight?
你今晚打算干什么
我爸妈冷战了 太烦了
My parents aren't speaking to each other, and it sucks.
They still married?
他们还没离婚吗
Yeah!
是啊
不过他们分开了
I mean, they're... separated.
Oh, I'm sorry.
啊 不好意思
I've been there, and it does suck.
我也经历过这个 确实很糟糕
等他们说开了 离婚了 就会舒服很多了
It gets easier after they just pull it together and divorce.
They are not getting divorced!
他们不能离婚
行吧
Okay.
I didn't mean to yell.
我不是特意对你吼的
我只是说 他们现在的情况很艰难
I-I just mean they're going through a bad time.
虽然现在事情很糟 但他们依然相爱啊
And... and, yes, things suck, but they still love each other,
这让我很焦躁 因为相爱的人就该在一起啊
which drives me crazy 'cause they should be together.
所以我要像电影《父母陷阱》那样撮台他们
So I'm going to "Parent Trap" them.
What the hell is a parent trap?
父母陷阱是什么玩意儿
You've never seen "The Parent Trap"?!
你没看过《父母陷阱》这部电影吗
Never heard of it. Not even the Lindsay Lohan one?
- 没听过 - 林赛-罗韩那部都没看过吗
I'm setting up a dinner date
我要给他们制造一场晚餐约会
for them so they'll be forced to talk
那么他们就不得不聊天了
然后重归于好 我们又是一家人了
and we can go back to being a family.
好机灵的想法
Oh, that's cute.
- 谢谢 - 同时也很可怕
Thanks. And terrible.
你不能让两个成年人
You cannot put two adults in a room for a playdate
把手里的事情丢到一边
and expect everything they're dealing with
陪你玩过家家
to get resolved over mac-and-cheese.
我一定要撮台他们 贾斯汀
I got to make this happen, Justine.
我妈妈已经在和她的男同事约会了 好像来真的
My mom's dating a guy at her job, and it might be serious.
叫加布 我可不能有个叫加布的后爸
Gabe... I can't have a stepdad named Gabe.
哦 内有隐情啊
Oh, so, there's a twist.
你爸对于这个加布什么看法
What does your dad think about Gabe?
没想法 因为他不知道这个人
Nothing, because he doesn't know Gabe exists,
我也不打算告诉他
and I am not going to tell him.
我不想再让他生气了
I don't want to upset him any more...
通过告诉他可能有个
By letting him know another dude...
年轻力壮 又高又帅的男人
Presumably younger, hotter, and taller...
在和他妻子暧昧吗
Is banging his wife?
哎 是
Ugh.
身为一个快乐小孩 你的生活一团糟
You have a messed-up life for a happy kid.
我可太好奇了
I'm into it.
Uh, hello?
喂 你好
Hi.
你好
Why won't you talk to me?
为什么你不和我说话
Huh?!
啊
Didn't mean to scare you.
不好意思 吓到你了
I'm running to class but wanted to check and see
我正去教室呢 但我想先问问
if we're still on for tonight.
我们今晚还要不要值班
Tonight? Uh...
今晚吗 呃
Undergrads. No respect for office hours.
本科生 一点都尊重工作时间
Ever. Yeah.
- 从来都不听话 - 对啊
So? Yeah, yeah!
- 所以我们今晚 - 啊对对
Yeah, we're on. We're on, yes.
是的 我们要值班 没错
Definitely. Your place, 9:00.
你的班次在九点
Not 8:00?
不是八点吗
Maddie's making me dinner, remember?
麦蒂给我了晚饭 记得吗
♪ Oh, yeah
Amma. How's your foot?
阿妈 你的脚怎么样了
Oh, I'm fine, beta-a-a.
我好着呢 宝贝
Don't worry about me-e-e.
不要操心我
Hey! No!
啊 不要
No!
不
Uh!
I remember!
我想起来了
You're... you're one of the others from the slums.
你们 你们是贫民窟里的人
He killed you first?
他们先把你们杀了吗
Is... is this real?
这是真的吗
Am I dead?
我死了吗
So, is Lowell in there?
洛厄尔在里面吗
If I rub the server, does she come out?
如果我洗劫服务器 她会出来吗
It's just a recursive copy of her source.
这只是她源代码的递归副本
Only the parts of her needed to attack our network.
只要泄露一部分她就能攻击我们的网络
Well, it was enough.
那就够了
After the whack she gave us, I need to shore up capital
自从她重击我们之后 我就得筹集资金
to keep the lights on here.
才能让这里不断电
Can't you just move money from product services or, uh...
你不能只从产品服务申转移资金吗 或者 呃
Not my area.
我不太清楚这一块
I'll be four time zones away but still reachable,
我要去四个时区以外的地方 但是你们还能联系到我
so let me know if something pops up from Kim or Lowell or...
如果金和洛厄尔有什么动静 立刻通知我
Problem with the kid!
那个小孩出问题了
He's written a script to search for redacted locations
他写了个脚本 在谷歌地球上
on Google Earth, including cached images.
搜索已有位置 包括缓存图像
There's a ton of redacted places.
里面有成千上百的緩存图片呢
How'd he get to Norway?
他要怎么去挪威呢
Cross-referenced our public financial disclosures.
交叉引用了我们公开的财务报告
Found our... Our donations to the Ocean Fund.
- 找到我们的··· - 我们对海洋基金的捐款
Clever as ever. Can you head him off?
一如既往地聪明 你们能先他一步拦截他吗
I'm in Google's database, swapping out
我在谷歌的数据库里 正在抹除
the cached images now.
相关缓存图
Too late. He found us.
太晚了 他找到我们了
他找到建筑工地的存档图了
He's got archived photos of the construction site.
Whoa.
哇
What the hell?
什么情况
And... we're gone.
好 图片消失术
Whoosh. Are you kidding?
- 鸣呼 - 你开什么玩笑
He found us.
他找到我们了
He didn't get a screenshot.
他没截图呢
He can't prove anything. Saken er biff.
他什么都证明不了 没有证据
Don't Norwegian this! He saw you change the image.
别用挪威语装腔了 他看着你更改图片的
He knows.
他知道了
Everything he knows
他所知的一切
is about to end tomorrow.
明天都会结束
Call me if there's a change.
事情有变再通知我
Butternut squash soup.
胡桃南瓜汤
Farm to factory, to box, to Trader Joe's, to table.
农场生产 工厂加工 装盒上市 再端上桌
As nature intended.
真是纯天然
Smelling.
气味
I forgot about smelling.
都快忘了什么是气味了
Mom! Can you come help me with the couscous?
妈 能帮我搞下这个蒸粗麦粉吗
I'll be down in a second.
马上下来
She thinks I'm cooking for World Cultures Day.
她还以为我在为世界文化日准备吃的呢
Maybe this isn't such a good idea.
我感觉这不一定行得通
Don't worry. You look great.
别担心 你看起来很不错
I called Mom.
我之前给你妈打过电话了
At her office.
她上班的时候
What?! Dad! Dad, I told you I would handle it!
什么 爸爸 我说过让我来处理这件事
I was going to! Sorry.
- 我正要去和她说呢 - 抱歉
She hung up on me.
她把我电话挂了
I don't know why I... Maddie, that smells amazing.
- 我也不知道为什么我··· - 麦蒂 太香了
Our daughter has become quite the chef.
我们的女儿可真是大厨咯
Thanks, Dad.
多谢夸奖 爸爸
Have a seat.
请坐吧
Maddie, can I talk to you?
麦蒂 我们能谈谈么
Sure. Have some soup.
当然可以 先喝点儿汤吧
I'm sorry I surprised you at work.
对不起 那时候吓到你了
I-I-I just really need to talk to you.
我只是想和你谈谈
Mom!
妈妈
This is not okay, and you know it.
这绝对不行 你应该知道的
Why are you being like this?!
你为什么要这样
You know where I stand.
你知道我的立场
You made a choice to disregard my feelings.
但你却选择无视我的感受
And what about his feelings?!
那他的感受呢
You're breaking his heart!
你伤透了他的心
This isn't human, Maddie! It doesn't feel!
他不是人了 哪来的感受 麦蒂
It's Dad! It's David Kim!
这就是爸爸 是大卫·金
Okay! It's your father.
行 这是你爸爸
But it's not my husband.
但它绝不是我丈夫
Because you can't have sex with him?
因为你不能和他上床吗
What? Whatever!
- 什么  - 随便吧
Just... Just go, okay?
你尽管走吧 好吗
Go to Gabe.
你去找加布吧
你精心打扮 不就是为了去见他吗
That's what you dressed up for.
No, no, no.
不 不行
We're gonna talk right now.
我们现在就得谈谈
Good.
好啊
I meant me and you.
我是说 你和我
Whatever you say to me, you can say to him.
有什么是能和我说 不能和他说的
Ellen...
埃伦...
please.
求你了
你什么时候准备好了 再来找我吧
When you're ready to talk, let me know.
Sorry, Dad.
抱歉 爸爸
Dad?
爸爸
爸爸 你还在吗
Dad, are you there?
Who's Gabe?
加布是谁
Huh?!
啊
What's wrong?
怎么了
Sorry. Can we change this?
不好意思 我们能看点儿别的吗
Sure. In fact, watch this.
行 那看看这个
No more zombies.
这次没有僵尸了
I'd rather watch you.
我宁愿看看你
我是不是得打趣一下这性感的电流
I feel like I should make a joke about our sexual electricity,
but that if I do, we won't actually have sex again.
但我要是真说了 估计你再也不想和我亲密了
Oh, yeah, follow that impulse.
就 继续这种感觉吧
♪ Hey, I'm still alive ♪ Huh?! Sorry.
抱歉
That's weird.
真是奇了怪了
♪ Hey, I'm still alive ♪
♪ Hey, I ♪
♪ Hey, I, oh ♪
Stop it, David! I'm serious.
住手 大卫 我认真的
David? Ugh!
- 大卫 - 啊
You mean your ex?
你是说你前夫么
Ugh, yes.
对
No.
也不对
我以为我们已经说开了
I thought we talked about this.
Ellen...
埃伦
发生什么了
what's going on?
好吧 我开始有点儿不爽了
Okay, I'm... I'm starting to get real uncomfortable.
对不起
I'm sorry.
You have to tell me what's really going on,
你必须告诉我到底怎么了
or I can't do this.
否则我继续不下去
Gabe...
加布
I...
我...
can't.
不能说
怕我理解不了吗
Because I wouldn't understand
or believe, right?
还是怕我会不相信
That's what you said,
你是这个意思吗
怕我不相信你
because I wouldn't believe you?
Try me.
试试吧 好吗
Please don't.
别这样
What? Finish that sentence.
什么 你说完
"Please don't" what?
"别"哪样
I can't do anything you want or don't want
如果你不和我说 我怎么知道你想要什么
if you don't talk to me.
又不想要什么
Ellen: How does this work?
这个怎么用
What are you doing?
你在干什么
好了 这 他在里面吗
Okay, is... What, is he in there?
I need to talk to him. Now.
我要和他说话 快点
What is this?
这是什么
我这是...
What am I...
- 没穿衣服吗 - 这就是你
not wearing? You're you.
我参考你的照片 以蛮族女祭司的身体造型为基础
I custom-built you an avatar out of some photo reference
给你定做了个身体
and used the barbarian-priestess body as a base.
你认真的吗
Seriously?
埃伦
Ellen...
David.
大卫
两年前我就告诉过你
I told you...
就算你真成功了
two years ago that if you did this,
it wouldn't be you.
这也不是真正的你
Not to me.
对我来说不是
- 我明白 - 不 你不明白
I know. No, you don't,
because it's not you.
因为这根本不是你
但又 确实是你
And it is you.
你能明白吗
Do you understand?
我搞不清楚你到底是什么
I don't know what you are.
我不能...
I can't be someone who...
I can't be with you like this.
不能像这样陪着你
Look, I get it.
听着 我明白的
We said "till death do us part."
我们曾说"至死不渝"
然后我死了
And I died.
Then...
但现在...
I came back.
我回来了
You died!
你已经死了
Two horrible years, I mourned you.
在这糟糕透的两年里 我一直在为你哀悼
I woke up crying every day!
我每天都哭着醒来
Then, I finally moved on.
然后好不容易 我决定向前看
I found a new house because the old one reeked of you.
我找了处新房子 因为老房子里满是你的气味
I found a great guy... One who helped me realize
我新处的对象也很好 他让我清醒过来
that you were in the grave, not me.
让我意识到死去的是你 而不是我
I had to move on, David.
我必须向前看 大卫
You have to let me keep moving.
你得放我走 让我继续向前生活
I know.
我知道
我很抱歉 我会放手
I'm sorry. I... I will.
Dad?
爸爸
All I ask of you... is the same.
但我想说的 也是如此
你不知道我是谁 其实我自己也搞不明白
You don't know what I am? Well, neither do I.
I can't explain what it feels like to be where I am
我也解释不清这种感觉 我是我自己吗
or where I'm not.
还是说 我已不是我
I know I'm not the man you knew.
我知道我不再是从前的我
But when you said I wasn't... human...
但当你说 我不是···人的时候
Oh, God, I'm sorry.
天呐 对不起
Listen to me.
听我说
I don't know what I am, but I do know who I love.
我不知道我是谁 但我知道我爱着谁
I love Maddie...
我爱麦蒂...
and I love you.
我爱你
And this love is what I am.
而这些爱就是我的存在
Without it, I stop moving.
没有这些 我寸步难行
And I need to keep moving, too.
我也需要继续向前啊
我还是不能继续做你的妻子
I can't be your wife.
But we can keep talking.
但我们可以保持联系
也许···
And maybe...
we can both keep moving.
这样我们就都能向前了
This must be, hands down, the weirdest breakup
亳无疑问 这肯定是人类历史上
in human history.
最为古怪的分手场景了
确实 开拓人类历史新领域了
Oh, yeah, this is new ground.
阿姆斯特朗 这次你输了
Neil Armstrong, eat your heart out.
Four?
需要四片吗
前三片 缓解疼痛
First three were for the pain.
Mm, ah.
最后一片是想不听见你的声音
I'm hoping this one will drown out the sound of your voice.
痛苦
You want pain?!
你还想跟我谈痛苦
You want to talk about pain?!
我真是受够你了
I am... I am done with you!
Done!
受够了
把你的手从我脸上拿开
Get your finger out of my face!
卡里 卡里
Cary! Cary!
Put it down!
把它放下
放下
Put it down!
这是你自找的
You asked for this!
Oh. Uh...
你认真的吗
Are you serious?
你知道这对他来说意味着什么吗
Do you know what this meansfor him?
对未来意味着什么
For the future?
Do you?
你呢
Caspian! Don't hurt him!
凯斯宾 不要伤害他
凯斯宾 凯斯宾 求求你了
Caspian, Caspian, please!
No!
不要
你··· 你们两个
You... You two...
真是蛇鼠一窝
deserve each other.
不 卡里
No! Cary!
回来
Come back!
你刚刚犯下了人生中最大的错误 儿子
You just made the biggest mistake of your life, son.
这里的一切...
All this...
都属于我
Mine.
You two will be out on the streets soon,
你们两个马上就会流落街头
因为不用我再给钱 你们就会饿死
because I'll see you dead before I feed you another dime.
No! No!
不 不
No.
不要啊
No. What are we gonna do?
不 我们要怎么办
我们要怎么办 我们...
What are we gonna do? What are...
先带你去医院
We're gonna get you to the hospital.
之后我会照顾我们俩的
And then I'm gonna take care of us.
Alright, well, the Pearl Jam thing was rude.
好吧 珍珠果酱那事很过分
I mean, I thought Gabe was gonna pee himself.
我觉得加布会尿裤子
但是呢
But?
But I laughed on the way home.
但是我在回家路上笑起来了
哇哦
Oh, wow.
What?
怎么了
我刚想起来 这是我今晚第二次分手了
I just remembered, this was my second breakup
of the night.
你的感情生活真悲剧
Your love life is tragic.
嘿
Hey!
Hey.
没错 是这样 不过...
It is. It is, but...
我 耶 耶
♪ I, yeah-eah, yeah
♪ I'm still alive
我仍旧充满活力
嘿 嘿 我
♪ Hey, hey, I
♪ Oh, oh, I'm still alive
♪ Yeah, I, oh, I'm still alive ♪
♪ Hey, I, oh, I'm still alive ♪
♪ Oh, yeah
嘿
Hey.
我有没有和你讲过艾迪·维达约我出去那次
Did I ever tell you about the time Eddie Vedder asked me out?
他找你问路
He asked you for directions.
你当时不认识那个乐队
And you didn't know them.
没人想听你讲
One one wants your input.
他在说什么
What's he saying?
你爸正在说
Your... Oh, your dad is saying
他很感激我在他的鼎盛时期
he's grateful that I turned down the hottest living grunge star
拒绝了史上最性感的垃圾摇滚明星
when he was in his Samson-haired prime,
记住了 这样我就能和他约会
mind you, so that I could date him instead
最后生下了你
and end up having you.
他可没这么说
He said none of that.
That's my girl.
这才是我的好闺女
谢谢你让我的生活步入正轨
Thanks for kicking my ass into gear.
I needed that.
当时的我非常需要
Congratulations, Cary. How do you feel?
祝贺你 卡里 现在感觉如何
你知道吗 他把我揍了一顿
You know, he kicked the hell out of me.
老实说 当时有一秒真的很恐怖
Got pretty scary for a second, honestly.
你没事吧 你需要治疗吗
You okay? You need medical attention?
No, no, I...
不用 我...
我得准备好向上汇报
I should be able to make it to the debrief.
- 出什么事了 - 没事
- What's wrong? - Nothing.
The inflection point was met.
转折点到了
计划如期进行
Right on schedule.
卡里 直说吧
Cary, come on.
我...
I'm...
I'm gonna miss him, that's all.
我会想他的 就这样
你很快就会再见到他的
- You'll see him again soon. - I know.
- 他是科技和商业领域的领导人之一 - 我知道
He's one of the leading voices in tech and business...
我明天跟凡-卢万确认一下
I'll check in with Van Leuwen tomorrow,
但我想现在就告诉你 你做得很棒
but I want you to hear me now... Good job.
欢迎来到全球科技论坛
Please welcome to the Global Tech Forum,
Julius Pope, CEO of Logorhythms.
欢迎朱利叶斯·蒲柏 字符律动的首席执行官
我得挂了
Gotta go.
在斯蒂芬-霍尔斯特隆逝世后
So, we are approaching the 20th anniversary
of our world without Stephen Holstrom in it.
我们的公司马上就要迎来第20周年了
It's crazy to think about.Yeah.
- 这很疯狂 - 是的
And I'm sure you've been sick of this question
至少在最近十年内 想必您已经
- 厌倦这个问题了 - "斯蒂芬会怎么说"吗
for at least a decade... "What would Steve say?"
不 我并没厌倦这个问题
No, I'm not sick of the question.
- 我们每天都会自问这个问题 - 现在还是吗
We ask it every day. Still?
现在还是 并且永远如此
Still, and always.
好 那么您觉得对于我们的工业
Okay, well, then what do you think
如今已经陷入人工智能军火竞赛这件事
Stephen would say about the artificial intelligence
arms race that our industry has fallen into?
斯蒂芬会怎么说呢
我认为答案会很短 只有一个词
Well, I imagine it would be short... one word.
一个我不能在这里说的词
One that I can't say here.
"上载"
"Upload."
这便是霍尔斯特隆真正
That's the dirty word Holstrom
想大声说出来的肮脏之词
would really want to say out loud.
Why expand machine intelligence
明明人脑已经有了最好的操作系统
when you've got the best operating system right here?
为什么还要发展人工智能呢
Careful, there.
小心点儿
虽然你看不见 但是隔墙有耳
You can't see 'em, but there's ethics watchdogs everywhere,
sniffing around.
总会有人审判道德
That hasn't stopped us, though, has it?
但这并不能阻我们 不是吗
There's an "us"? There can be.
- 你说的是"我们"吗 - 可以有
A joint patent. One-time offer.
联合专利 一次性报价
我们的下一位嘉宾是度最大电信集团的负责人
Our next speaker is the head of India's largest telecom empire.
Think about it.
考虑一下吧
You have 10 seconds. What have you done?
- 你有10秒钟的时间思考 - 你做了什么
He is responsible for connecting over one billion people.
他将十亿多人联系在一起
5 seconds.
还剩5秒
这不是什么仿制的手机或芯片 阿吉特
This isn't some knock-off phone or chip, Ajit.
This is dangerous tech.
这是一项很危险的技术
You don't want to play with it.
你是不会想参与进来的
Knock-off?
仿制吗
You's a Stephen Holstrom knock-off.
你还是假冒的斯蒂芬．霍尔斯特隆呢
Not even that.
甚至连那都算不上
阿吉特·普拉萨德 联盟电信的首席执行官
Ajit Prasad, CEO of Alliance Telecom!
Know what else you're not?
还知道你自己不是什么吗
You're not the only game in town anymore.
你不再是游戏里唯一的玩家了
How do we get out of here?
我们要怎么逃出去
My God.
我的天
I... I can't do that.
我...我做不到
I don't know how!
我不知道要怎么做
Spiking again?
又增强了吗
Gotta wipe you clean, Chanda.
得把你清除了 钱达
Sorry.
对不起了
Hi.
嗨
You didn't do anything wrong.
你没说错什么
You were trying to be a friend,
你是想和我做朋友
我那时候很尴尬
and I was embarrassed,
所以我封闭了自己的内心
so I shut down.
I'm really sorry, Hannah.
我真的很抱歉 汉娜
I like you.
我喜欢你
Could I take you out?
我可以约你出去吗
On a real date?
真正地约会一次
Like in the '50s or the...'90s,
就像旧时候的人们那样
whenever people did that.
就那种约会
Just so you know, I wasn't trying to be a "friend."
你要知道 我不只是想当"朋友"
Good.
那就好
♪ Are you a man or a monster?
♪ It's so hard to tell which side you're on ♪
♪ One day is Hell
♪ The next day is the dawn
♪ The lines are blurred
♪ You keep rubbing your eyes
♪ The tables turn
♪ Now it's time to survive
Amma. How's your foot?
阿妈 你的脚怎么样了
Oh, I'm fine, beta. Don't worry about me.
我好着呢 贝塔 不用操心我
Or if you want to worry, worry about making me a grandmother.
不过你要是真的担心我
操心操怎么让我当上奶奶吧
Like all my friends are.
我所有的朋友都当奶奶了
♪ Are you a man or a monster?
♪ A man or a monster?
♪ Ohh, oh-oh oh oh
♪ Are you a man or a monster?